<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<lfm status="ok">
<artist>
  <name>Raunchy</name>
  <mbid>72c81780-1f0f-482c-88c5-6e80788a36f7</mbid>
  <url>http://www.last.fm/music/Raunchy</url>
  <image size="small">http://userserve-ak.last.fm/serve/34/48010407.jpg</image>
  <image size="medium">http://userserve-ak.last.fm/serve/64/48010407.jpg</image>
  <image size="large">http://userserve-ak.last.fm/serve/126/48010407.jpg</image>
  <image size="extralarge">http://userserve-ak.last.fm/serve/252/48010407.jpg</image>
  <image size="mega">http://userserve-ak.last.fm/serve/500/48010407/Raunchy+ronni_2010.jpg</image>
  <streamable>1</streamable>
  <stats>
    <listeners>56694</listeners>
    <playcount>2036373</playcount>
      </stats>

  <similar>
	    <artist>
	  <name>Sybreed</name>
	  <url>http://www.last.fm/music/Sybreed</url>
	  <image size="small">http://userserve-ak.last.fm/serve/34/93977.jpg</image>
	  <image size="medium">http://userserve-ak.last.fm/serve/64/93977.jpg</image>
	  <image size="large">http://userserve-ak.last.fm/serve/126/93977.jpg</image>
	  <image size="extralarge">http://userserve-ak.last.fm/serve/252/93977.jpg</image>
	  <image size="mega">http://userserve-ak.last.fm/serve/500/93977/Sybreed.jpg</image>
	</artist>
    <artist>
	  <name>Mnemic</name>
	  <url>http://www.last.fm/music/Mnemic</url>
	  <image size="small">http://userserve-ak.last.fm/serve/34/364574.jpg</image>
	  <image size="medium">http://userserve-ak.last.fm/serve/64/364574.jpg</image>
	  <image size="large">http://userserve-ak.last.fm/serve/126/364574.jpg</image>
	  <image size="extralarge">http://userserve-ak.last.fm/serve/252/364574.jpg</image>
	  <image size="mega">http://userserve-ak.last.fm/serve/500/364574/Mnemic.jpg</image>
	</artist>
    <artist>
	  <name>Disarmonia Mundi</name>
	  <url>http://www.last.fm/music/Disarmonia+Mundi</url>
	  <image size="small">http://userserve-ak.last.fm/serve/34/281174.jpg</image>
	  <image size="medium">http://userserve-ak.last.fm/serve/64/281174.jpg</image>
	  <image size="large">http://userserve-ak.last.fm/serve/126/281174.jpg</image>
	  <image size="extralarge">http://userserve-ak.last.fm/serve/252/281174.jpg</image>
	  <image size="mega">http://userserve-ak.last.fm/serve/500/281174/Disarmonia+Mundi.jpg</image>
	</artist>
    <artist>
	  <name>The Interbeing</name>
	  <url>http://www.last.fm/music/The+Interbeing</url>
	  <image size="small">http://userserve-ak.last.fm/serve/34/16301301.jpg</image>
	  <image size="medium">http://userserve-ak.last.fm/serve/64/16301301.jpg</image>
	  <image size="large">http://userserve-ak.last.fm/serve/126/16301301.jpg</image>
	  <image size="extralarge">http://userserve-ak.last.fm/serve/252/16301301.jpg</image>
	  <image size="mega">http://userserve-ak.last.fm/serve/_/16301301/The+Interbeing.jpg</image>
	</artist>
    <artist>
	  <name>Blinded Colony</name>
	  <url>http://www.last.fm/music/Blinded+Colony</url>
	  <image size="small">http://userserve-ak.last.fm/serve/34/137919.jpg</image>
	  <image size="medium">http://userserve-ak.last.fm/serve/64/137919.jpg</image>
	  <image size="large">http://userserve-ak.last.fm/serve/126/137919.jpg</image>
	  <image size="extralarge">http://userserve-ak.last.fm/serve/252/137919.jpg</image>
	  <image size="mega">http://userserve-ak.last.fm/serve/500/137919/Blinded+Colony.jpg</image>
	</artist>
  </similar>
    <tags>
        <tag>
	  <name>metalcore</name>
	  <url>http://www.last.fm/tag/metalcore</url>
	</tag>
        <tag>
	  <name>melodic death metal</name>
	  <url>http://www.last.fm/tag/melodic%20death%20metal</url>
	</tag>
        <tag>
	  <name>industrial metal</name>
	  <url>http://www.last.fm/tag/industrial%20metal</url>
	</tag>
        <tag>
	  <name>metal</name>
	  <url>http://www.last.fm/tag/metal</url>
	</tag>
        <tag>
	  <name>modern metal</name>
	  <url>http://www.last.fm/tag/modern%20metal</url>
	</tag>
      </tags>
      <bio>
    <published>Wed, 18 Aug 2010 00:08:20 +0000</published>
    <summary><![CDATA[Raunchy was founded in Denmark, in 1992 by Jesper Tilsted, Jesper Kvist, and Morten Toft Hansen, who start jamming, playing mostly cover from bands like Metallica and Slayer. Lars Vognstrup and Lars Christensen join in 1994, and in 1995 they record their first demo, at Borsing Recordings in Århus. The song &quot;Space Story&quot; from the demo is later released on the compilation CD Extremity Rising vol. 1, a rock compilation from Serious Entertainment. Two demos (and two more Extremity Rising inclusions later) the band finally get their record deal, with Mighty Music's sub label Drug(s) in 2000.]]></summary>
    <content><![CDATA[Raunchy was founded in Denmark, in 1992 by Jesper Tilsted, Jesper Kvist, and Morten Toft Hansen, who start jamming, playing mostly cover from bands like Metallica and Slayer. Lars Vognstrup and Lars Christensen join in 1994, and in 1995 they record their first demo, at Borsing Recordings in Århus. The song &quot;Space Story&quot; from the demo is later released on the compilation CD Extremity Rising vol. 1, a rock compilation from Serious Entertainment. Two demos (and two more Extremity Rising inclusions later) the band finally get their record deal, with Mighty Music's sub label Drug(s) in 2000. A few months later Raunchy enters the Aabenraa Studio with producer Jacob Hansen to record Velvet Noise. In 2001 the album is released in Scandinavia and is very received by the press.[citation needed] After the release Jeppe Christensen joins the band.  2002 proves to be a crucial year for the band: as the first Danish band ever Raunchy signs a contract with one of the world biggest metal labels, Nuclear Blast Records, who release Velvet Noise is released in Europe. Raunchy plays at the German festival Summerbreeze. They record a cover of Wham!'s &quot;Last Christmas&quot; and a new song called &quot;Decemberklar&quot; for Denmark's National radio, produced by Tue Madsen at Antfarm Studios. The songs prove to be very popular. Raunchy also performs live in the radio-studio; the performance is taped by Danish Television and broadcast as well. In 2003 the Velvet Noise is released in North America, and in the summer the second album, Confusion Bay, is recorded, again with producer Jacob Hansen.  The year 2004 starts off with singer Lars Vognstrup leaving the band. Kasper Thomsen is recruited as the new front man, and in February Confusion Bay is released. An animated video for the track &quot;Watch Out&quot; is made by the critically acclaimed director Anders Morgenthaler and the video receives airplay on channels like VIVA+ and MTV2. The band perform a whole concert live on Danish National Radio, and in August the band perform at the Wacken in front of 4,000 fans.  In 2005 Death Pop Romance is recorded, mixed by Tue Madsen and released with a new label, Lifeforce Records. At the end of the year the band performs at the Danish Metal Awards. The show is broadcast live on the Danish radio and marks the band's third radio appearance. Death Pop Romance is released to good reviews in 2006.[citation needed] Raunchy supports legendary band Soulfly on all German dates. Apparently Max Cavalera is pleased enough with their performance to give the band more stage time after only two shows. The band also plays at the legendary With Full Force Festival in Leipzig before 10,000 fans. In 2006, the band continued to tour to support Death Pop Romance and with support gigs behind them for such acts as Ill Nino and Hatebreed, the band embarked on a full-length European tour called Danish Dynamite Tour, together with Hatesphere and Volbeat, and playes at 2008's Roskilde Festival.  In summer 2008 Raunchy released their fourth album Wasteland Discotheque, produced, mixed and mastered by Jacob Hansen. and is very received by the press. In late 2008 Raunchy went on a small tour with Volbeat in Germany. In April 2009, almost a year after Wasteland Discotheque was released, Raunchy did a music video for the track &quot;Warriors&quot;, directed by Andreas Krohn, after that they went on a tour called &quot;Weekend Warriors Tour&quot;, in Denmark and Sweden, and in July and August the band played at the big metal festivals With Full Force and Summer Breeze Open Air.  Their fifth album, A Discord Electric, is set for a September 20th, 2010 release.   Current members Kasper Thomsen - Vocals (2004 -) Lars Christensen - Guitar (1994 -) Jesper Andreas Tilsted - Guitar (1994 -) Jesper Kvist - Bass (1994 -) Jeppe Christensen - Keyboard/Vocals (2001 -) Morten Toft Hansen - Drums (1994 -)  Former members Lars Vognstrup - Vocals (1994 - 2004)
    
User-contributed text is available under the Creative Commons By-SA License and may also be available under the GNU FDL.]]></content>
  </bio>
  </artist></lfm>
