<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<lfm status="ok">
<artist>
  <name>Demon's Claws</name>
  <mbid>5ec6ffc4-b291-4471-8839-cfe2d3d0437a</mbid>
  <url>http://www.last.fm/music/Demon%27s+Claws</url>
  <image size="small">http://userserve-ak.last.fm/serve/34/90897.jpg</image>
  <image size="medium">http://userserve-ak.last.fm/serve/64/90897.jpg</image>
  <image size="large">http://userserve-ak.last.fm/serve/126/90897.jpg</image>
  <image size="extralarge">http://userserve-ak.last.fm/serve/252/90897.jpg</image>
  <image size="mega">http://userserve-ak.last.fm/serve/_/90897/Demons+Claws.jpg</image>
  <streamable>1</streamable>
  <stats>
    <listeners>11459</listeners>
    <playcount>107831</playcount>
      </stats>

  <similar>
	    <artist>
	  <name>The Spaceshits</name>
	  <url>http://www.last.fm/music/The+Spaceshits</url>
	  <image size="small">http://userserve-ak.last.fm/serve/34/2125943.gif</image>
	  <image size="medium">http://userserve-ak.last.fm/serve/64/2125943.gif</image>
	  <image size="large">http://userserve-ak.last.fm/serve/126/2125943.gif</image>
	  <image size="extralarge">http://userserve-ak.last.fm/serve/252/2125943.gif</image>
	  <image size="mega">http://userserve-ak.last.fm/serve/_/2125943/The+Spaceshits.gif</image>
	</artist>
    <artist>
	  <name>Mark Sultan</name>
	  <url>http://www.last.fm/music/Mark+Sultan</url>
	  <image size="small">http://userserve-ak.last.fm/serve/34/26261611.jpg</image>
	  <image size="medium">http://userserve-ak.last.fm/serve/64/26261611.jpg</image>
	  <image size="large">http://userserve-ak.last.fm/serve/126/26261611.jpg</image>
	  <image size="extralarge">http://userserve-ak.last.fm/serve/252/26261611.jpg</image>
	  <image size="mega">http://userserve-ak.last.fm/serve/_/26261611/Mark+Sultan+4.jpg</image>
	</artist>
    <artist>
	  <name>Oblivians</name>
	  <url>http://www.last.fm/music/Oblivians</url>
	  <image size="small">http://userserve-ak.last.fm/serve/34/35154769.jpg</image>
	  <image size="medium">http://userserve-ak.last.fm/serve/64/35154769.jpg</image>
	  <image size="large">http://userserve-ak.last.fm/serve/126/35154769.jpg</image>
	  <image size="extralarge">http://userserve-ak.last.fm/serve/252/35154769.jpg</image>
	  <image size="mega">http://userserve-ak.last.fm/serve/_/35154769/Oblivians.jpg</image>
	</artist>
    <artist>
	  <name>Cheap Time</name>
	  <url>http://www.last.fm/music/Cheap+Time</url>
	  <image size="small">http://userserve-ak.last.fm/serve/34/21172057.jpg</image>
	  <image size="medium">http://userserve-ak.last.fm/serve/64/21172057.jpg</image>
	  <image size="large">http://userserve-ak.last.fm/serve/126/21172057.jpg</image>
	  <image size="extralarge">http://userserve-ak.last.fm/serve/252/21172057.jpg</image>
	  <image size="mega">http://userserve-ak.last.fm/serve/_/21172057/Cheap+Time+2745184342_d7ff79df82.jpg</image>
	</artist>
    <artist>
	  <name>Les Sexareenos</name>
	  <url>http://www.last.fm/music/Les+Sexareenos</url>
	  <image size="small">http://userserve-ak.last.fm/serve/34/9110.jpg</image>
	  <image size="medium">http://userserve-ak.last.fm/serve/64/9110.jpg</image>
	  <image size="large">http://userserve-ak.last.fm/serve/126/9110.jpg</image>
	  <image size="extralarge">http://userserve-ak.last.fm/serve/252/9110.jpg</image>
	  <image size="mega">http://userserve-ak.last.fm/serve/_/9110/Les+Sexareenos.jpg</image>
	</artist>
  </similar>
    <tags>
        <tag>
	  <name>garage rock</name>
	  <url>http://www.last.fm/tag/garage%20rock</url>
	</tag>
        <tag>
	  <name>garage punk</name>
	  <url>http://www.last.fm/tag/garage%20punk</url>
	</tag>
        <tag>
	  <name>garage</name>
	  <url>http://www.last.fm/tag/garage</url>
	</tag>
        <tag>
	  <name>canadian</name>
	  <url>http://www.last.fm/tag/canadian</url>
	</tag>
        <tag>
	  <name>rock n roll</name>
	  <url>http://www.last.fm/tag/rock%20n%20roll</url>
	</tag>
      </tags>
      <bio>
    <published>Fri, 5 Oct 2007 03:48:06 +0000</published>
    <summary><![CDATA[Montreal in the last ten years has undoubtedly been a bastion of rootsy, homemade rock'n roll that moves people in a serious way. There's something about the majority of people who 'get it' vs. those who don't that makes that city such a great breeding ground, and the Demon's Claws are the latest pioneers to make their way out with an intimidating shove. Formed from members of the Scat Rag Boosters and the Cut Offs looking for a way to break down music to it's simplest parts, but without any of the snobby aloofness of post-punk, they hit the nail on the head with a winning formula.]]></summary>
    <content><![CDATA[Montreal in the last ten years has undoubtedly been a bastion of rootsy, homemade rock'n roll that moves people in a serious way. There's something about the majority of people who 'get it' vs. those who don't that makes that city such a great breeding ground, and the Demon's Claws are the latest pioneers to make their way out with an intimidating shove. Formed from members of the Scat Rag Boosters and the Cut Offs looking for a way to break down music to it's simplest parts, but without any of the snobby aloofness of post-punk, they hit the nail on the head with a winning formula. And with a range that qualifies them as possessors of real talent, they mangle authentic country cuts right along with their tight, 2-chord tonal tantrums which no bar fight would be complete without. When most people think of guitar twang, devils and deer skulls usually aren't the first images that come to mind, so when you see a group of guys conjuring up that old rockin' black magic sound, it's already got the darkness on it's side, much like the early 80s LA death-punk collective. Like the cold feel of an evil autumn breeze, there's something very antagonistically comforting about the Demon's Claws ability to lure you in their direction, whether it's your intent or not. And just when you're close enough to feel the warmth of the flames, they switch gears and blow up right in your face with a pummeling stomper of a song like &quot;Wrong Side of Town&quot; that reminds you that you're definitely still a mortal who enjoys the occasional trollop like everyone else. They stride through their new album, Satan's Little Pet Pig, with pain, agonizing soul, and precision, and with the addition of Perpignan's rowdiest Mighty Go-Go Player, Piero Ilove joining the band on electric piano, their live shows just got another deranged shot of insanity sauce. While their recent performances truly exalted the indubitable power of their songs more than the production on their first LP did, this new album, done up right by Mike McHugh at his Distillery Studios, has brought the ferocity, power, and puissance to full fruition. This album, their debut for In The Red, should cast no shadow of a doubt as to their intent to bring their genuine sound up from the underground, and it's such a relief that after all we've been taught in life, it's the demons that can save us after all.
    
User-contributed text is available under the Creative Commons By-SA License and may also be available under the GNU FDL.]]></content>
  </bio>
  </artist></lfm>
